There are some rules of thumb when looking at correlation coefficients.
هناك بعض القواعد العامة عند التركيز على عوامل الارتباط؛
However, this is a highly field-dependent measure.
لكن هذا قياس يستند إلى طبيعة المجال بدرجة عالية.
In the social sciences,
في العلوم الاجتماعية،
it can be very hard to find strong relationships because humans are complex.
قد يكون من الصعب جدًا أن نعثر على علاقات قوية نظرًا لأن البشر كائنات معقدة.
So the boundaries for the correlation coefficient for
إذًا فحدود عامل الارتباط
this field tend to be very different than say,
في هذا المجال تميل إلى الاختلاف بشدة عن.. لنقُل عن
the environmental associations that we find.
الرابطات البيئية التي نعثر عليها.
So again, this is just a rule of thumb.
إذًا نقول مجددًا، هذه مجرد قاعدة عامة.
If a correlation coefficient is between 1 and 0.7,
إذا كان معامل ارتباط فيما بين 1 و0.7،
or between negative 1 and negative 0.7,
أو بين -1 و-0.7،
this is considered a strong relationship.
فتُعتبر هذه العلاقة قوية.
If it's between 0.7 and 0.3,
إذا كان المعامل بين 0.7 و0.3،
or negative 0.7 and negative 0.3,
أو بين -0.7 و-0.3،
this is considered a moderate relationship.
فتُعتبر هذه العلاقة معتدلة.
And if the absolute value is below 0.3,
وإذا كانت القيمة المطلقة أقل من 0.3
then this is considered a weak relationship.
فتُعتبر هذه العلاقة ضعيفة.
Remember, a negative correlation coefficient is not indicative of a weak relationship.
تذكَّروا أن معامل الارتباط السالب ليس مؤشرًا على علاقة ضعيفة.
Additionally, a plot can assist in
فضلًا عن ذلك، يمكن لمخطط أن يساعدنا
better understanding the relationships between two variables.
في فهم العلاقات بين متغيرين بصورة أفضل.
If we take two of the images from Anscombe's quartet,
إذا أخذنا صورتين من رباعية Anscombe
notice that these two data sets have the exact same correlation coefficient.
فلاحِظوا أن مجموعتي البيانات هاتين لهما نفس معامل الارتباط،
However they look very different.
ومع ذلك فإنهما تبدوان مختلفتين بشدة.